ebay.ca 2014-10-09

# User Privacy Notice

User Privacy Notice

Posted and effective for new users: August 19, 2014 

Effective for current users: September 19, 2014

Previous version: March 26, 2013[](http://privacy.truste.com/privacy-seal/eBay-Inc-/validation?rid=ee496e33-69a1-49b4-9c88-e752d34b4cfb)

### Summary & Contents

| 

**Scope and Consent**

| 

This Privacy Notice describes our collection, use, disclosure, retention, and protection of your personal information. It applies to any eBay site where this Privacy Notice appears in the footer, and to any eBay application, service, or tool (collectively "Services") where this Privacy Notice is referenced, regardless of how you access or use them, including through mobile devices.  By using our Services and/or registering for an account with us, you are accepting the terms of this Privacy Notice and our [User Agreement](http://pages.ebay.ca/help/policies/user-agreement.html), and consenting to our collection, use, disclosure and retention of your personal information as described in this Privacy Notice.

Learn more.  
  
---|---  

**Global Privacy Standards**

| 

eBay Inc. has established global privacy standards for all eBay Inc. companies known as Binding Corporate Rules (BCRs). They are our commitment to protect your personal information and honour our privacy obligations regardless of where your personal information is collected, processed or stored.

Learn more.  
  
**Collection**

| 

We collect personal information from you and the devices (including mobile devices) you use to access or use our Services.  Categories of personal information we collect include, but are not limited to personal information:

  * you give us when you use our Services

  * we collect automatically when you use our Service

  * we collect using Cookies, Web Beacons and Similar Technologies

  * we collect or obtain from other sources

Learn more.  

**Use and Retention**

| 

We use the personal information we collect to: operate, improve and personalize our Services, to contact you about your account or our Services, provide you customer service, customize our advertising and marketing, and to detect, prevent and mitigate fraudulent or illegal activities.

We retain your personal information as long as it is necessary and relevant for our operations. In addition, we retain personal information from closed accounts to comply with the law, prevent fraud, collect any fees owed, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigation, enforce our User Agreement and take other actions permitted by law.

Learn more.  

**Choice**

| 

You have a choice about how we use your personal information to communicate with you, send you marketing information, and provide you with customized and relevant advertising.

Learn more.  
  
**Access**

| 

We take steps to ensure that the personal information we collect is accurate and up to date, and that you have the ability to access it or make corrections to it.

Learn more.  
  
**Disclosure**

| 

There are times when we disclose your personal information to members of the eBay Inc. corporate family or other third parties. This disclosure may be required for us to operate or provide you access to our Services, comply with our legal obligations, enforce our policies, facilitate our advertising, or reduce or prevent fraud related to our Services. We do not disclose your personal information to third parties for their marketing and advertising purposes without your explicit consent.

Learn more.  
  
**Security**

| 

We protect your information using technical and administrative security measures to reduce the risks of loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure and alteration. Some of the safeguards we use are firewalls and data encryption, physical access controls to our data centers, and information access authorization controls.

Learn more.  
  
**Important Information**

| 

This section describes some additional important information related to your use of our Services. Please review it for more details.

Learn more.  
  
**Questions or Complaints**

| 

If you have a question or a complaint about this Privacy Notice or our global privacy or information handling practices, you can reach our Global Privacy Office in writing by sending us a letter or postcard to: eBay Inc, Attn: Legal - Global Privacy Office, 2145 Hamilton Avenue, San Jose, California 95125 USA.  See the full section for more information on how to contact us.

Learn more.  
  
### Scope and Consent

This Privacy Notice describes your privacy rights regarding our collection, use, disclosure, retention, and protection of your personal information. It applies to any eBay site where this Privacy Notice appears in the footer, and to any eBay application, service, or tool (collectively "Services") where this Privacy Notice is referenced, regardless of how you access or use them, including through mobile devices. 

By using our Services and/or registering for an account with us, you are accepting the terms of this Privacy Notice and our [User Agreement](http://pages.ebay.ca/help/policies/user-agreement.html), and you are consenting to our collection, use, disclosure and retention of your personal information as described in this Privacy Notice and in our User Agreement. If you do not provide the information we require, we may not be able to provide all our Services to you.

If you reside in the United States, you are contracting with eBay Inc. 2145 Hamilton Avenue, San Jose, CA 95.125 USA. If you reside outside of the United States, you are contracting with one of our international eBay companies:

  * If you reside in a country within the European Union, you are contracting with eBay Europe S.à.r.l, 22-24 Boulevard Royal, L-2449, Luxembourg

  * If you reside in India, you are contracting with India Private Limited, 14th Floor, North Block, R-Tech Park, Western Express Highway, Goregaon (East), Mumbai 400063, Maharashtra India

  * If you reside in any other country, you are contracting with eBay International AG, Helvetiastrasse 15/17, 3005, Bern, Switzerland.

The company you are contracting with is your data controller, and is responsible for the processing of your personal information in accordance with our global privacy standards. Your data controller may transfer data to other eBay data controllers as described in this privacy notice. We may store and process your personal information on our computers in the US and elsewhere in the world where our data centers are located.

**Personal Information**

"Personal information" is information that can be associated with a specific person and could be used to identify that specific person whether from that data or from that data and other information that eBay has or is likely to have access to. We do not consider personal information to include information that has been made anonymous or aggregated so that it can no longer be used, whether in combination with other information or otherwise, to identify a specific person.

**Changes to this Notice**

We may amend this Privacy Notice at any time by posting the amended terms on this site. All amended terms automatically take effect 30 days after they are posted. We will notify you through the eBay Message Center and/or via email of any material changes to this Privacy Notice.

### Global Privacy Standards

eBay Inc. has established global privacy standards for all eBay Inc. companies known as our Binding Corporate Rules (BCRs). They are our commitment to protect your personal information and honor our privacy obligations regardless of where your personal information is collected, processed, or stored. Our BCRs have been approved by a number of European Union privacy regulators. More information about our BCRs and our global privacy practices and principles, including information on how to contact us, is available at our [eBay Privacy Centre](http://www.ebayprivacycenter.com/privacy).

### Collection

We collect personal information from you and the devices (including mobile devices) you use to access or use our Services. This personal information we collect includes, but is not limited to personal information of the kinds described below:

**Personal information you give us when you use our Services**

  * Identifying information such as your name, addresses, telephone numbers, e-mail addresses 

  * Bidding, buying, or selling information for a particular transaction or other transaction based content you generate or is connected to your account for that particular transaction 

  * Financial information such as credit card or bank account numbers in connection with a transaction 

  * Postage billing and other information to purchase or post an item, as well as, where postal services are provided through one of our programs, information required to clear customs (such as Tax ID or other identification numbers) and relevant postage information (tracking updates) stored by the chosen postal partner

  * In some instances, you may provide age, gender, interests and favorites

  * You may also provide us other information through your participation in community discussions, chats, dispute resolution, correspondence through our sites, or correspondence sent to us 

  * Additional information we are required by applicable law authorizes to request in order to authenticate or identify you to use or verify the information we have collected (such as under laws requiring the seller of second hand goods to provide authentication in any country) 

**Personal information we collect automatically when you use our Services**

We also collect information about your interaction with our Services, advertising, or e-mail communications. This is typically information we receive from your computer or other devices, including your mobile devices. 

  * Device ID or unique identifier, device type, ID for Advertising, unique device token

  * Geo-location information, including location information from your mobile device. Keep in mind that:

    * Most mobile devices allow you to control or disable the use of location services in the device's settings' menu.

    * You may also be presented with an additional notice explaining any additional information we may collect from you that is not listed in this notice.

  * Computer and connection information

  * Statistics on page views, traffic to and from the sites, referral URL, ad data, IP address, and browsing history and web log information ****

**Personal information we collect using Cookies, Web Beacons and Similar Technologies**

We use cookies, web beacons, unique identifiers, and similar technologies to provide and improve our Services and personalized advertising and marketing, and to provide safer experience and personalized experience on our sites. We collect information about the pages you view, the links you click, and other actions you take on our Services, or within our advertising or e-mail content. For more information about our use of these technologies and how to control them, see our notice on [Cookies, Web Beacons and Similar Technologies](http://pages.ebay.ca/help/account/cookies-web-beacons.html).

**Personal information from other sources**

  * We may supplement the information we collect with information from third parties and add it to your account information. For example, as permitted by law, we may collect demographic information that is publically available, additional contact information, credit check information, and information from credit bureaus as allowed by law. We may combine information you give us with information we collect from other sources and use it for any purpose disclosed in this privacy notice.

  * We may allow you to share information with third party social media sites, or use social media sites or other sites to create or connect to your account. Those social media sites may give us access to certain personal information stored by them (e.g., content viewed and information about the advertisements within the content you have been shown or may have clicked on, etc.) from your interaction with the online services. You agree that we may share your video viewing with, or obtain information about your video viewing from, third-party social media sites for at least two years or until you withdraw consent. Remember that you control the personal information you allow us to have access to through the privacy settings on that third party site and the permissions you give us when you grant us access. By associating an account managed by a third party with your eBay account and authorizing eBay to have access to this information, you agree that eBay may collect, use and store the information provided by these sites in accordance with this privacy notice.

  * If you give us personal information about someone else, you must do so only with their consent.  You agree to inform them that we have collected their personal information and tell them how we collect, use and disclose the personal information.

### Use and Retention

We use the personal information we collect to operate, improve and personalize our Services, to contact you and provide you customer service, customize our advertising and marketing, and to detect, prevent and mitigate fraudulent or illegal activities. You agree that we may use your personal information as follows:

**Operate, improve, and personalize our Services**

  * Provide you use of and access to our Services

  * Provide you site content that includes great products that we think you will like and keeps track of the collections and stores that you have chosen to follow 

  * Give you access to your purchase history, scores, bids, internal email and other features

  * Provide you with credit offers and opportunities on behalf of members of our corporate family and their financial institution partners (such as PayPal Credit, a PayPal service) who offer financial products. We do not share any financial information without your explicit consent

  * Customize, measure, and improve our sites, applications and Services

  * Provide other services requested by you as described when we collect the information

  * We may use geo-location information to provide you with location based services, such as advertising, search results, and other personalized content

**Contact you and provide you customer service**

  * Provide customer support you request for our Services or for the products offered by members of our corporate family and their financial institution partners (such as PayPal Credit, a PayPal service)

  * Contact you, either via email or telephone (using autodialed or pre-recorded calls), text (SMS) messages (if applicable) as authorized by you to resolve disputes, collect fees, and troubleshoot problems with your account or our Services and for other purposes authorized by law and consistent with this Privacy Notice

  * Compare the personal information you provide for accuracy, and verify it with third parties as necessary

**Customize our advertising and marketing communications with you**

  * Customize, measure, and improve our content and advertising based on your ad customization preferences

  * Contact you, either via email, telephone, text (SMS) messages (if applicable based on your consent), or postal mail, or otherwise as authorized by you to: offer coupons, discounts and special promotions, and inform you about our services and those of our corporate family. You agree that eBay will use the contact information you have provided to contact you by e-mail and/or SMS text if you have consented to such contact. Message and data rates may apply.

  * Deliver targeted marketing, service updates, and promotional offers based on your communication preferences

**Detect, Prevent and Mitigate Fraudulent or Illegal Activities**

  * Prevent, detect, and investigate fraud, security breaches, potentially prohibited or illegal activities

  * Enforce our User Agreement or other applicable policies

We retain your personal information as long as it is necessary and relevant for our operations. In addition, we retain personal information from closed accounts to comply with the law, prevent fraud, collect any fees owed, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigation, enforce our User Agreement and take other actions permitted by law. After it is no longer necessary for us to retain your personal information, we dispose of it in a secure manner according to our data retention and deletion policies.

### Choice

You have a choice about how we use your personal information to communicate with you, send you marketing information, and provide you with customized and relevant advertising.

**Communication Preferences**

You can control how and when you want to receive notifications from eBay about your buying and selling activities and the methods by which we may contact you from the Communication Preference section within your My eBay. You can also control your member-to-member communications preferences setting and choose which newsletters and promotions you want to receive.

**Marketing**

We do not sell or rent your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes without your explicit consent. If you do not wish to receive marketing communications from us, you can unsubscribe from the link in the email you received, change your Communication Preferences within My eBay or indicate your preferences within the direct communication from us.

**Advertising**

We do not allow third parties to track or collect your personal information on our site for their own advertising purposes without your explicit consent. If you do not wish to participate in our ad-customization programs, you can opt-out by following the directions provided within the applicable advertisement, or directly at our [Ad Choice program](http://pages.ebay.ca/help/account/adchoice.html). The effect of an opt-out will be to stop targeted advertising, but it will still allow the collection of usage data for certain purposes (e.g., research, analytics and internal online services operation purposes).

If you withdraw your consent for the use or disclosure of your personal information for the other purposes set out in this Privacy Notice you may not have access to our all our Services and we might not be able to provide you all of the Services and customer support offered to our users and authorized under this Privacy Notice and our User Agreement.

### Access

We take steps to ensure that the personal information we collect is accurate and up to date, and that you have the ability to access or correct it.

  * You can see, review and change most of your personal information by signing on to your account. Please update your personal information immediately if it changes or is inaccurate 

  * Once you make a public posting, you may not be able to change or remove it. Upon your request, we will close your account and remove your personal information from view as soon as reasonably possible, based on your account activity and in accordance with applicable law

  * We will honour any statutory right you might have to access, modify or erase your personal information. You can use the Contact Us to request access and find out whether any fees may apply, as permitted by law.  Where you have a legal right to request access or request the correction of information, we can still withhold that access or decline to correct information in some cases in accordance with applicable law, but will give you reasons if we do so.

### Disclosure

There are times when we disclose your personal information to members of the eBay Inc. corporate family or other third parties. This disclosure may be required for us to operate or provide you access to our Services, comply with our legal obligations, enforce our policies, facilitate our advertising, or reduce or prevent fraud related to our Services. We minimize the amount of personal information we share to what is directly relevant and necessary to accomplish the specified purpose. As stated above, we do not disclose your personal information to third parties for their marketing and advertising purposes without your explicit consent. 

We may disclose your personal information for the following purposes:

[**eBay Inc. Corporate family members,**](http://www.ebayprivacycenter.com/about-us/corporate-family) **who may use it to:**

  * provide joint content and services (like registration, transactions, and customer support) 

  * help detect and prevent potentially illegal acts, violations of our policies, or fraud and/or data security breaches

  * guide decisions about their products, sites, applications, services and tools, and communications

  * provide customized advertising

Members of our corporate family will use this information to send you marketing communications only if you have consented to receive such communications from them. 

If we were to merge with or be acquired by another company, we may share information with them in accordance with our Global Privacy Standards. Should such an event occur, we will require that the new combined entity follow this Privacy Notice with respect to your personal information. If your personal information will be used or disclosed for any purposes not covered in this Privacy Notice, you will receive prior notification of the use of your personal information for the new purposes.

**Service Providers and Financial Institutions Partners**

  * Third party service providers who help us operate our Services, and assist with fraud investigations, bill collection, affiliate and rewards programs, co-branded credit cards and other business operations

  * financial institution partners who may offer financial products to our users (such as WebBank and Comenity Capital Bank with whom we partner to provide PayPal Credit, a PayPal Service) to provide joint content and services (like registration, transactions and customer support), to help detect and prevent potentially illegal acts, violations of our policies, fraud and/or security breaches, and to guide decisions about their products, websites, applications, services, tools, and communications. These third party financial institution partners will use this information to send you marketing communications only if you have requested their services

**Law enforcement, legal proceedings, and as authorized by law**

  * to comply with our legal requirements, enforce our policies, respond to claims that a listing or other content violates the rights of others, or protect anyone's rights, property or safety 

  * to law enforcement or governmental agencies, or authorized third-parties, in response to a verified request relating to a criminal investigation or alleged or suspected illegal activity or any other activity that may expose us, you, or any other eBay user to legal liability. We will only disclose information we deem relevant to the investigation or inquiry,such as name, city, state, postcode, telephone number, email address, User ID history, IP address, fraud complaints, bidding and listing history, and anything else we deem relevant

  * to eBay VeRO Program participants under confidentiality agreement, as we in our sole discretion deem necessary or appropriate in connection with an investigation of fraud, intellectual property infringement, piracy, or other unlawful activity. In such events, we will disclose name, street address, city, state, postcode, country, phone number, email address and company name

  * to credit bureaus as authorized by applicable law (e.g. information on late or missed payments or other defaults on your account that may be reflected in your credit report)

  * to third parties involved in a legal proceeding, if they provide us with a subpoena, court order or substantially similar legal procedure, or we otherwise believe in good faith that the disclosure of information is necessary to prevent imminent physical harm or financial loss or to report suspected illegal activity.

**People you authorize us to provide it to**

  * eBay users as authorized by you or your use of our Services (e.g. if you buy an item the seller may view your email address and request and obtain your contact information, including phone number or email and postal address to help complete the transaction)

### Security

We protect your information using technical and administrative security measures to reduce the risks of loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure and alteration. Some of the safeguards we use are firewalls and data encryption, physical access controls to our data centers, and information access authorization controls.

### Important Information

There are just a few more pieces of important privacy information related to your use of our Services that we need to cover:

**When you share your personal information on eBay – what happens?**

Other users have access to the information you share on eBay. For example, other people can see your bids, purchases, items for sale, your collections, the members and collections you follow, storefronts, Feedback, ratings and associated comments. Other users can also see any information you chose to share in your profile or your collections. 

Your User ID is displayed throughout eBay and is available to the public. It is connected to all of your eBay activity. Notices sent to other community members about suspicious activity and notice violations on our sites refer to User IDs and specific items. So if you associate your name with your User ID, the people to whom you have revealed your name will be able to personally identify your eBay activities. 

To help protect your privacy, we allow only limited access to other users' contact, shipping and financial information as necessary to facilitate your transactions and collect payments. However, when users are involved in a transaction, they have access to each other's name, User ID, email address and other contact and shipping information.

**How you should use the information you receive on eBay**

eBay enables you to obtain personal information of others to complete transactions and collect payments. We encourage you to disclose your privacy practices and respect the privacy of other users. In all cases, you must give other users a chance to remove themselves from your database and a chance to review what information you have collected about them

Use the personal information that you have access to only for eBay transaction-related purposes, for using services offered through eBay (such as escrow, shipping, and fraud complaints), and for purposes expressly consented by the user to whom the information relates. Using personal information that you have access to for any other purpose is a violation of our policies.

**Unwanted or threatening email**

Sending unwanted or threatening email is against our [policies](http://pages.ebay.ca/help/account/unwanted-email.html) and constitutes a violation of our [User Agreement](http://pages.ebay.ca/help/policies/user-agreement.html?rt=nc). To report eBay-related spam or spoof emails please forward the email to [spam@ebay.com](mailto:spam@ebay.com) or [spoof@ebay.com](mailto:spoof@ebay.com).

**Children's Privacy**

Our websites are general audience websites, and our Services are not intended for children under the age of 13. We do not knowingly collect personal information from users in this age group.

**Third Party Privacy Practices**

This Privacy Notice addresses only the use and disclosure of personal information we collect from you. If you disclose your information to others, their privacy notices and practices will apply. 

We cannot guarantee the privacy or security of your information once you provide it to a third party and we encourage you to evaluate the privacy and security policies of your trading partner before entering into a transaction and choosing to share your information.  This is true even where the third parties to whom you disclose personal information are bidders, buyers or sellers on our sites.

### Questions or Complaints

If you have a question or a complaint about this Privacy Notice or our global privacy or information handling processes, you can reach the Global Privacy Office in writing by sending us a letter or postcard to: eBay Inc, Attn: Legal - Global Privacy Office, 2145 Hamilton Avenue, San Jose, California 95125, USA, or using the [Contact Us](http://contact.ebay.ca/ws/eBayISAPI.dll?ContactUsNextGen&domain=Help&query=Privacy%20policy&from=1003146) form for your individual site.

You can also find more information on how to contact us at our [eBay Privacy Center](http://www.ebayprivacycenter.com/about-us).

**Our previous Privacy Policy (effective for current users until September 18, 2014)**

**Your Privacy Rights**

 **Contents**

  *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *   *   * 

 **Scope and Consent**

This Privacy Policy describes how eBay International AG, with registered office at Helvetiastrasse 15-17, 3005 Bern, Switzerland, collects, uses, stores, shares and protects your personal information. It applies to the eBay.ca website and all related sites, applications, services and tools where this policy is referenced, regardless of how you access or use them. You can view a summary of this Privacy Policy at our [Privacy Summary Page](http://pages.ebay.ca/help/account/privacy-summary.html). More detailed information about our privacy practices and how to contact us with question is available at our[ eBay Privacy Centre.](http://www.ebayprivacycenter.com/)

Throughout this Privacy Policy, we use the term “personal information” to describe information that can be associated with a specific person and can be used to identify that person. We do not consider personal information to include information that has been made anonymous or aggregated so that it cannot be used, whether in combination with other information or otherwise, to identify a specific user.

By using eBay.ca and its related sites, applications, services and tools and/or registering for an eBay.ca account, you expressly consent to our collection, use, disclosure and retention of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy and in our User Agreement. We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time by posting the amended terms on this site.  All amended terms automatically take effect 30 days after they are initially posted on the site. Additionally, we will notify you through the eBay Message Centre and/or via email of any material changes to this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy is effective on March 26, 2013, for current users, and upon acceptance for new users. The previous amendment to this Privacy Policy was effective for all users on May 16, 2012.

 **Global Privacy Standards**

Our parent company, eBay Inc. has established a set of corporate rules for privacy, known as Binding Corporate Rules (BCRs), which are the global privacy standards for all eBay Inc. companies. These BCRs have been approved by a number of European Union privacy regulators.  They are a commitment by eBay Inc. to protect your personal information and honor our privacy obligations regardless of where your personal information is collected, processed or stored. Depending on where you reside, the BCRs may also provide you some additional privacy rights through your local privacy regulator or court. Some eBay-branded websites or websites may be governed by separate privacy policies. The privacy policy that applies will be the policy that is referenced by the respective website, application, service or tool. The privacy practices of our corporate family are consistent with those described in this Privacy Policy and our BCRs. More information about our BCRs and our global privacy practices and principles, including information on how to contact us with any questions, is available at our [eBay Privacy Centre.](http://www.ebayprivacycenter.com/privacy)

 **Mobile Privacy**

We may offer you the ability for you to connect with our sites, or use our applications, services and tools using a mobile device, either through a mobile application or via a mobile optimized website. The provisions of this Privacy Policy apply to all such mobile access and use of mobile devices. This Privacy Policy will be referenced by all such mobile applications or mobile optimized websites.

 **Collection of Personal Information**

You can browse the ebay.ca website, or relates sites, without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself. If you register for an account with us, you give us your personal information, and you are not anonymous to us. If you choose to provide us with personal information, you consent to the transfer and storage of that information on our servers located in the United States.

We collect the following types of personal information in order to provide you with the use of and access to our sites, applications, services and tools, and to help us personalize and improve your experience.

 **Information We Collect Automatically**

When you visit our sites, use our applications, services and tools, or interact with our advertising or content, we automatically collect information sent to us by your computer, mobile device, or other access device.  This information is associated with you personally only when sign in as a registered user, and includes but is not limited to:

  * device ID or unique identifier, device type, geo-location information, computer and connection information, statistics on page views, traffic to and from the sites, referral URL, ad data, IP address and standard web log information,

  * anonymous information collected through our use cookies and web beacons

**Information You Give Us**

We collect and store any information you enter on our sites or you provide to us in context of using our sites, applications, services or tools. This may include, but is not limited to:

  * information you provide us when registering for an account, including email address, phone number, mobile telephone number, physical contact information, and (depending on the service used) sometimes financial information, such as credit card or bank account numbers;

  * addition information you may provide to us via social media sites or services

  * transactional information based on your activities on the sites (such as bidding, buying, selling, item and content you generate or that relates to your account);

  * shipping, billing and other information you provide to purchase or ship an item;

  * information provided in the context of community discussions, chats, dispute resolution, correspondence through our sites, or correspondence sent to us

  * additional personal information we ask you to submit to authenticate yourself or if we believe you are violating site policies (for example, we may ask you to send us an ID or bill to verify your address, or to answer additional questions online to help verify your identity or ownership of an item you list)

 **Mobile**

When you download or use our Mobile Applications, or access one of our mobile optimized sites, we may receive information about your location and your mobile device, including a unique identifier for your device.  We may use this information to provide you with location based services, such as advertising, search results, and other personalized content. Most mobile devices allow you to control or disable location services in the device’s setting’s menu.  If you have questions about how to disable your device’s location services, we recommend you contact your mobile service carrier or the manufacture of your particular device.

 **Information from other Sources**

We may receive or collect supplemental information about you from third parties sources and add it to our account information. This may include, but is not limited to, demographic and navigation information, credit check information, and additional information about you from a credit bureau or other sources, as permitted by law.

 **Information Collection, Sharing and Registration - Social Media Websites** 

We offer sign-on services that allow you to use third party login credentials to access the eBay.ca and related sites. We also offer services that allow you to share information with third party social media websites such as Facebook, Google Plus, Twitter, and others.

You may choose to provide us with access to certain personal information stored by such third party websites. The personal information we have access to varies by website and is controlled by your privacy settings on that website and your consent.  By associating an account managed by a third party with your eBay account and authorizing eBay to have access to this information, you agree that eBay may collect, use and store information from these websites in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

 **Use of Personal Information**

Our primary purpose in collecting personal information is to provide you with access to our sites and/or use of our services, applications and tools, provide you with requested customer service and relevant information about your account and our services, and to provide you with a safe, smooth, efficient, and customized experience. You agree that we may use your personal information to:

  * provide you access to our sites and the services and customer support you request;

  * prevent, detect, and investigate, fraud, security breaches, potentially prohibited or illegal activities, and enforce our User Agreement;

  * customize, measure and improve our services, content and advertising;

  * contact you, either via email or telephone, to resolve disputes, collect fees, and troubleshoot problems with your account or our sites, services, applications or tools, or for other purposes authorized by law

  * contact you, either via email or telephone  to inform you about our services and those of our corporate family, deliver targeted marketing, service updates, and promotional offers based on your communication preferences

  * compare information for accuracy, and verify it with third parties;

  * contact you at any telephone number using auto-dialed or pre-recorded message calls or text (SMS) messages (if applicable) as authorized for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy

  * provide you other services requested by you as described when we collect the information

 **Marketing**

You agree that we may use your personal information to tell you about our and our corporate family’s websites, applications, services and tools, deliver targeted marketing and promotional offers based on your communication preferences, and customize measure and improve our advertising, based on your ad customization preferences.

We do not sell or rent your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes without your consent. We may combine your personal information with information we collect from other companies and use it to improve and personalize our advertising and marketing to you.

 **Opting Out of the use of Personal Information**

If you do not wish to receive marketing and promotional communications from us, you can indicate your communications preference in your [My eBay page,](http://pages.ebay.ca/help/account/my-ebay.html)or within the direct communication from us. If do not wish to participate in our ad-customization programs, you can opt-out by following the directions provided within the applicable advertisement, or directly at our [Ad Choice program.](http://pages.ebay.ca/help/account/adchoice.html)

If you withdraw your consent for the use or disclosure of your personal information for the other purposes set out in this Privacy Policy we may not be able to continue to allow you to have access to our websites, applications, or tools, or to provide you with some or all of the services and customer support offered to our users and authorized under this Privacy Policy and our [User Agreement](http://pages.ebay.ca/help/policies/user-agreement.html?rt=nc).

 **Our Disclosure of Your Information**

We disclose personal information to respond to legal requirements, enforce our policies, respond to claims that a listing or other content violates the rights of others, or protect anyone's rights, property, or safety. Such information will be disclosed in accordance with applicable laws and regulations. As stated above, we do not disclose your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes without your explicit consent.

We may also share your personal information with:

  * [Members of the eBay Inc. corporate family](http://www.ebayprivacycenter.com/about-us/corporate-family) to provide joint content and services (like registration, transactions and customer support), to help detect and prevent potentially illegal acts and violations of our policies, and to guide decisions about their products, sites, applications, tools, services and communications. Members of our corporate family will use this information to send you marketing communications only if you have requested their services and will use your personal information in compliance with their respective privacy policies and our global privacy standards.

  * Service providers under contract who help with our business operations (such as, but not limited to, fraud investigations, bill collection, affiliate and rewards programs, website operations, and co-branded credit cards).

  * Other eBay users, whether located in your country of residence or outside of your country of residence, as authorized by you or your use of our sites, services, applications or tools. For example, where you are involved in a transaction with another user, the other user may view your email address and request and obtain your contact information and postal address to help complete the transaction;

  * Other third parties to whom you explicitly ask us to send your information (or about whom you are otherwise explicitly notified and consent to when using a specific service).

  * Law enforcement or regulatory agencies, or authorized third-parties, in response to a verified request relating to a criminal investigation or alleged illegal activity or any other activity that may expose us, you, or any other eBay user to legal liability. In such events, we will disclose information relevant and necessary to the investigation or inquiry, such as name, city, state or province, provincial postal code, telephone number, email address, User ID history, IP address, fraud complaints, bidding and listing history, and anything else we may deem relevant to the investigation.

  * Credit bureaus with which we might report information about your account, including information on late payments, missed payments, or other defaults on your account may be reflected in your credit report.

  * eBay VeRO Program participants under confidentiality agreement, as we in our sole discretion believe necessary or appropriate in connection with an investigation of fraud, intellectual property infringement, piracy, or other unlawful activity. In such events, we will disclose name, street address, city, state, provincial postal code, country, phone number, email address and company name.

  * Other business entities, should we plan to merge with or be acquired by that business entity. Should such a combination occur, we will require that the new combined entity follow this Privacy Policy with respect to your personal information. If your personal information will be used or disclosed for any purposes not set out in this policy, you will receive prior notice.

While we use contractual and other measures to ensure protection of personal information, the laws and regulations relating to privacy and personal information protection in other jurisdictions may not be the same as, or similar to, your local privacy laws. The governments, courts, law enforcement or regulatory agencies in these other jurisdictions may be able to request disclosure of personal information through the laws of these countries. In an effort to respect your privacy, we will not otherwise disclose your personal information to law enforcement, other government officials, or other third parties without a subpoena, court order or substantially similar legal procedure, except when we believe in good faith that the disclosure of information is necessary to prevent imminent physical harm, financial loss, to report suspected illegal activity, or otherwise keep the community free from bad actors.

 **Information You Share on eBay**

Your User ID is displayed throughout eBay (and so available to the public), and is connected to all of your eBay activity. Other people can see your bids, purchases, items for sale, storefronts, Feedback, ratings and associated comments. Notices sent to other community members about suspicious activity and policy violations on our sites refer to User IDs and specific items. So if you associate your name with your User ID, the people to whom you have revealed your name will be able to personally identify your eBay activities.

If you access our websites from a shared computer or a computer in an internet café, certain information about you, such as your User ID, activity or reminders from eBay, may also be visible to other individuals who use the computer after you.

 **Using Information from eBay**

eBay enables you to share personal and financial information to complete transactions and collect payments. We encourage you to disclose your privacy practices and respect the privacy of other users. We cannot guarantee the privacy or security of your information and therefore we encourage you to evaluate the privacy and security policies of your trading partner before entering into a transaction and choosing to share your information. To help protect your privacy, we allow only limited access to other users' contact, shipping and financial information to facilitate your transactions and collect payments. When users are involved in a transaction, they may have access to each other's name, User ID, email address and other contact and shipping information. In all cases, you must give other users a chance to remove themselves from your database and a chance to review what information you have collected about them.

You agree to use user information only for:

  * eBay transaction-related purposes that are not unsolicited commercial messages;

  * using services offered through eBay (such as escrow, shipping, and fraud complaints), or

  * other purposes that a user expressly chooses.

 **How we use Cookies**

When you access our websites, or use our applications, and/or services and tools, we may place small data files on your computer or other device.  We use these data files, commonly known as “Cookies”, to help us identify you as a user, customize our services, content and advertising,  to measure promotional  effectiveness, and to promote trust and safety. For more detailed information on our use of Cookies, see [Cookies and Your Privacy](http://pages.ebay.ca/help/account/cookies-web-beacons.html).

A few important things you should know about our use of Cookies:

  * We offer certain features that are available only through the use of Cookies

  * We use both session and persistent Cookies. Session Cookies expire and no longer have any effect when you log out of your account or close your browser. Persistent Cookies remain on your device until you erase them or they expire

  * You are always free to decline Cookies if your browser permits, although doing so may interfere with your use of our websites, applications, and/or services and tools. Refer to the help section of your browser, browser extensions, or installed applications for instructions on blocking, deleting, or disabling Cookies

  * We encode and protect our Cookies so that only we can interpret the information stored in them

  * You may encounter Cookies from third parties, known as service providers, that we have allowed on our site that assist us with various aspects of our web site operations and services

  * You also may encounter Cookies from third parties on certain pages of the websites that we do not control and have not authorized. (For example, if you view a web page created by another user, there may be a cookie placed by that web page)

 **No Spam, Spyware or Spoofing**

We and our users do not tolerate spam. Make sure to set your eBay communication preferences so we communicate to you as you prefer. You are not licensed to add other eBay users, even a user who has purchased an item from you, to your mailing list (email or physical mail) without their express consent. To report eBay-related spam or spoof emails to eBay, please forward the email to [spam@ebay.com](mailto:spam@ebay.com) or [spoof@ebay.com](mailto:spoof@ebay.com). You may not use our communication tools to send spam or otherwise send content that would violate our User Agreement. We automatically scan and may manually filter messages to check for spam, viruses, phishing attacks and other malicious activity or illegal or prohibited content, but we do not permanently store messages sent through these tools. If you send an email to an email address that is not registered in our community (via Refer-a-Friend or other tools), we will not rent or sell that email address.

 **Accessing, Reviewing and Changing Your Personal Information**

Your password is the key to your account. Use unique numbers, letters and special characters, and do not disclose your eBay password to anyone. If you do share your password or your personal information with others, remember that you are responsible for all actions taken in the name of your account. If you lose control of your password, you may lose substantial control over your personal information and may be subject to legally binding actions taken on your behalf. Therefore, if your password has been compromised for any reason, you should immediately notify eBay and change your password.

You can see, review and change most of your personal information by signing on to eBay. Generally, we will not manually modify your personal information because it is very difficult to verify your identity remotely. You must promptly update your personal information if it changes or is inaccurate. Once you make a public posting, you may not be able to change or remove it.

 **Protecting and Storing Your Personal Information**

We store and process your personal information on our computers in the United States and elsewhere in the world where our facilities are located. We protect your information using technical and administrative security measures to reduce the risks of loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure and alteration. Some of the safeguards we use are firewalls and data encryption, physical access controls to our data centres, and information access authorization controls.

We take steps to ensure that the personal information we collect is accurate and up to date, and we provide you with the opportunity to update your information through your account profile settings.

 **Closing Your Account; Retention of Personal Information**

Upon your request, and subject to the provisions in this section, we will close your account and, as soon as reasonably possible, remove your personal information so that it cannot be viewed by other users. Removal will be based on your account activity and in accordance with applicable law. We may also close or deactivate inactive accounts, or accounts that are used in violation of our [User Agreement](http://pages.ebay.ca/help/policies/user-agreement.html?rt=nc).

In general, personal information from closed or inactive accounts will be deleted or rendered anonymous as soon as reasonably possibly after the account is closed or deactivated. Under certain circumstances we may retain personal information from closed or inactive accounts for longer. Grounds for doing so would include; prevention of fraud, collection of fees owed, resolution of disputes, to enforce our eBay User Agreement, or to otherwise take actions permitted by law. Under such circumstances this information will be kept as long as it is necessary and relevant for our operations, and to comply with any applicable law.

 **Third Parties**

Except as otherwise expressly included in this Privacy Policy, this document addresses only the use and disclosure of information we collect from you. If you disclose your information to others, whether they are bidders, buyers or sellers on our websites or other websites throughout the internet, different rules may apply to their use or disclosure of the information you provide to them. eBay does not control the privacy policies of third parties, and you are subject to the privacy policies of those third parties where applicable. We encourage you to ask questions before you disclose your personal information to others.

 **Contact Us**

If your questions are not answered online, you may write to us at: eBay Inc. Attn: Legal - Global Privacy Practices, 2145 Hamilton Avenue, San Jose, California 95125, or using the [Contact Us](http://ocs.ebay.ca/ws/eBayISAPI.dll?ContactCS) form. More information about the Global Privacy Office or how to contact us is available at our [eBay Privacy Centre.](http://www.ebayprivacycenter.com/about-us)

Contact Customer Support

| | 

If you're looking for more help or have a question to ask, please [contact us.](http://contact.ebay.ca/ws/eBayISAPI.dll?ShowCUPortal)   

---|---|---  
  
| 

Contact us

 ****Have a question? We can help.

Get help from other eBay members. Visit the [Answer Centre](http://pages.ebay.ca/community/answercenter/index.html) to post a question.
